Aaron Marr

Front-End Developer

☑ aaron.marr@icloud.com७ +44 7808 668 716

★ aaronmarr.co.uk

in linkedin.com/in/aaron-marr/

Profile

Hello, I'm Aaron. I'm a web developer based in Cornwall, UK.

I've been creating websites and software for over ten years. Currently, I'm helping to develop a network analytics product at Headforwards for NTT Network Innovations.

Right now, I'm specialised in Front-End development. But what makes me tick is building products and sites that put users first. I enjoy working in agile teams and solving real problems for the business and its users. I'm interested in putting my skills to work in the tech-for-good, 3rd sector, or Education space.

Work History

Front-End JavaScript Developer @ Headforwards

March 2019 - Present // Pool, UK (On Site)

Building a network monitoring tool for NTT Network Innovations

- Front-End Development using React
- Designed a state management solution with React Query and Zustand
- Set up and implemented End-to-End Testing solution with Playwright
- · CI/CD implementation with GitHub Actions

Building a suite of analytics tools for Plum ESG

- Full-Stack Javascript development using React and Express
- · Charts and data visualisations using D3 / Visx / Recharts
- · State management using React Hooks and Redux
- REST API Design and Development using Express and PostgreSQL
- · Accessibility-first Front-End design and development
- Supporting team in the adoption of a new tech stack (Node.js + React)

Senior Web Developer @ Colateral

April 2017 - March 2019 // Redruth, UK (Part Remote)

Building a suite of production workflow management tools for the retail industry

- Develop a large-scale Software-as-a-Service product using React and Redux
- · Write clean, scalable CSS using Sass and BEM
- Roll out a unit test suite using Mocha and Enzyme
- Build services and APIs using Node.js and Django
- · Work as part of a small, cross-functional team in a start-up environment

Front-End Developer @ Torchbox

April 2016 - April 2017 // Bristol, UK (Fully Remote)

Front-End Development for Django and Wagtail Websites for the Charity Sector

- Build bespoke Front-Ends for Wagtail websites using HTML5, Sass and JavaScript
- · Advocate for styleguide-driven development using PatternLab
- Implement modular Sass architectures using BEM and ITCSS methodologies
- Develop custom JavaScript libraries using ES6 and Babel Starter Kit

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript, Python, Ruby, PHP, HTML5, Sass, CSS

Libraries and Frameworks

React, Redux, Django, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, D3, jQuery, Vue, Tailwind,

Tools and Platforms

VSCode, Vim, Git, Docker, Linode, Heroku, MacOS, Linux

Design

Typography, grids, Design Systems, wireframes, prototypes

Education

Falmouth University

Sept 2013 - Sept 2014

Postgraduate Certificate in Higher Education

Falmouth University

Oct 2007 - June 2010

Bachelor of Arts in Digital Media

University of East Anglia

July 2006 - July 2007 Foundation Degree in Computing

Volunteering

Code Club

2017

Run a Code Club (part of Raspberry Pi Foundation) for 11 to 12 year olds, including sessions on Scratch, Python, and event-driven programming using JavaScript

Work History (continued)

Front-End Developer @ Freelance

October 2015 - April 2016 // Redruth, UK (Fully Remote)

Working as a freelance developer for Codebase 8

- · Consult and advise on Front-End Sass and HTML5 template architectures
- Promote component-driven development using a range of Front-End frameworks
- · Create custom, white-label Twitter Bootstrap themes
- · Rapid prototyping using Ruby on Rails

UX/UI Developer @ Dewsign

July 2015 - October 2015 // Falmouth, UK (On Site)

Front-End Development for a range of bespoke Websites built using WordPress

- Lead on Front-End development for websites built using WordPress
- · Develop custom WordPress themes and plugins
- · Improve development workflows using Docker

UX/UI Developer @ Headforwards

October 2014 - July 2015 // Pool, UK (On Site)

UX Design and Front-End Development for Enterprise Cloud (NTT Communications)

- Front-End Development using JavaScript (Backbone), HTML5 and Sass
- · Design key interface elements, using wireframes and interactive prototypes
- · Unit testing using Mocha and Chai

Learning Information Designer @ Falmouth University

July 2012 - September 2014 // Falmouth, UK (Part Remote)

UX Design and Front-End Development for Falmouth University's Learn platform

- · Front-End development using HTML5, JavaScript (jQuery) and Sass
- UX/UI design, including wireframes, story boards and interactive prototypes
- · Responsive web design

Learning Technologist (Intern) @ Falmouth University

September 2011 - July 2012 // Falmouth, UK (Part Remote)

Designing and Developing a range of internal websites using WordPress

· Web design and development for a range of internal systems and websites

Colophon

This CV was designed using <u>HTML</u> and <u>CSS</u> (<u>Tachyons</u>) using a <u>Macbook Pro</u> and <u>VSCode</u>. The fonts used are <u>SF Pro and SF Mono</u> by <u>Apple</u>. The icons are from <u>Font Awesome</u>. The <u>HTML source</u> is rendered to PDF using a <u>Python script</u> and the <u>Weasyprint</u> library.

Other Interests

Down time

Music, Craft Ale, Single Malt Whisky, family time, walks, Cornwall